Shaktman Associates Records
Shaktman Associates Records
1983-2008
Shaktman Associates
13 linear feet
Records of the international presentation skills training company founded by American playwright and director Ben Shaktman. Correspondence subject files; publications; memorabilia, including photographs and appointment calendars; and media, including audiotapes, VHS tapes, and computer floppy disks.
4046332
Biographical History
Founded in 1983 by American playwright and director Ben Shaktman, Shaktman Associates is an international presentation skills training company based in Santa Monica, CA. The company conducts workshops, coaches executives and publishes training material for a wide range of corporate clients.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Shaktman Associates Records spans the years 1983-2008 and is divided into four groups: Correspondence-subject files, Publications, Media, and Memorabilia.
Correspondence-subject files is arranged alphabetically and includes letters to and from and information about Shaktman Associates' clients as well as general correspondence.
Media includes audio, video, and computer material produced by Shaktman Associates as well as its clients and partners.
Memorabilia contains appointment calendars, phone logs, photgraphs, and a diary from Ben Shaktman's trip to China in 2000.
Publications includes workshop materials and handouts as well as general Shaktman Associates brochures and advertising material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by type or title.
Related Material
See also the
Ben Shaktman Papers
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Dance and theatre; Shaktman, Ben, 1937-; Carden, William.; International Business Machines Corporation.; Allianz Group.; Andersen Consulting.; Apple Computer, Inc.; Autodesk, Inc.; Claris Corporation.; Computer Sciences Corporation.; CRM Learning (Firm); Deloitte & Touche.; Electronic Data Systems Corporation.; Forrester (Firm); Gartner Group.; General Electric Company.; Guthy-Renker (Firm); Inforum (Firm); Infosys Technologies Ltd.; Insead.; London Business School.; META Group.; MediaWorks (Firm); Morgan Stanley & Co.; Polaroid Corporation.; Price, Waterhouse & Co.; Texas Instruments Incorporated.; Xerox Corporation.; Management -- United States -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Business presentations.; Executive coaching.; Communication in management.; Business communication.; Audiotapes.; CD-ROMs.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Drafts (documents); DVDs.; Floppy disks.; Lecture notes.; Mini-DV.; Photographs.; Research notes.; VHS.; Audiocassettes.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ben Shaktman: 1984, 1986, 1987, 1989, 1991, 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, 1998, 2000, 2001, 2003, 2004, 2006, 2007, 2008, 2009.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - General correspondence, 1983-2000; 24 folders (Box 1)
  - General correspondence, 2001-2006; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Ahern, Terry, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
  - [Sam] Albert Associates, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Albrezzi, Steven, 1984-1991 (Box 2)
  - Alden Design, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Allianz, 1988-2007; 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Andersen Consulting, 1988-1994; 24 folders (Box 2)
  - Apple, 1985-1986; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Apple, 1987-1995; 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Applied Business Technology, 1994-1998; 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Applied Business Technology, 1999-2000; 10 folders (Box 4)
  - Autodesk, 1994-1997; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - A.X.A., 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Belkin Productions, Inc., 1988 (Box 4)
  - Bell South, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
  - Bromka, Elaine, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Businessland, Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - Businessland, Inc., 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - Carden, William., 1988-2003; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Chamberlain, Jeffery D., 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Claris Corp., 1989 (Box 4)
  - Cochrane, Stuart S., 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Computer Sciences Corporation, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Construction Industry Solutions, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Copyright, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - CRM Films, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Delivering Project Excellence Conference, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Deloitte and Touche, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Devo Team, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Drake and Scull, 1997-1998 (Box 5)
  - Electronic Data Systems, 1987-1994; 10 folders (Box 5)
  - Farb Company, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Fish, Robert Stevens, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Forrester Research, Inc., 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Forte Software, 1998 (Box 5)
  - The Gartner Group, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Gay, Andrew, 2001 (Box 5)
  - General Electric, 1989; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - GIGA, 2000-2005; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Goodman, Burt, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Goss, Richard E., 2000-2002 (Box 6)
  - Greenleaf, Barbara, 1991-1993 (Box 6)
  - Goodman, Burt, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Grossman, Herb, 1998-2002; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Gruber, Michael, 1987-1989 (Box 6)
  - Gunthy-Renker, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Hirschowitz, Ralph G., 1987 (Box 6)
  - Hokus Pokus Productions, 1993 (Box 6)
  - I.B.M., 1983-1989; 12 folders (Box 6)
  - I.B.M., 1990-1992; 14 folders (Box 7)
  - I.B.M., 1993-2004; 13 folders (Box 8)
  - Inforum, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Infomart Dallas, Texas, 1985-1988 (Box 8)
  - Infomart model, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Inforum, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Infosys, 2004-2006; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Insead, 2001-2006; 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Intel Corporation, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Jarvis, PLC, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Jennings, David A., 1986 (Box 9)
  - Jones, Michael L., 1992-1993 (Box 9)
  - Kirchman Corporation, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
  - Klemper, Cees, 2005 (Box 9)
  - Lefkoe and Associates, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Levinson, Richard, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Lightwave Productions, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Litz, Robert, 1995 (Box 9)
  - London Business School, 2005-2008 (Box 9)
  - Lowe, Peter, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Marigold Associates, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Mediaworks, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Meta Group, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Mignon, Laurent, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Milken Institute, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Morgan Stanley and Company, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Nugent-Head, Tim, 2004 (Box 9)
  - O'Connor, Geoffrey, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Park, Russell D., 2002 (Box 9)
  - Polaroid, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Pratt, Daniel W., 1987 (Box 9)
  - Price Waterhouse Coopers, 1998-2008; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Public Relations Society of America, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Raphael, Lisa, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Rasmus, Daniel W., 2002 (Box 9)
  - Rosenak, David S., 1986 (Box 9)
  - Sacharow, Neal, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Schoonover Associates, 1985-1991; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Schreiber, Terry, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Schubert, Peter, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Schwartz, Alan, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Shames, Deborah, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Shaktman Associates Training Program, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Siemens, 1997-2000 (Box 10)
  - Software 2000, 1992-1993 (Box 10)
  - Stellar, Patricia Ann, 1991-1992 (Box 10)
  - Stephenson, Karen, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Streamline Holdings, Ltd., 1999 (Box 10)
  - Tassin, Philippe, 1998-2005 (Box 10)
  - Telleen, Steve, 2004-2005 (Box 10)
  - Texas Instruments, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Unger, Deborah, 1986-1987 (Box 10)
  - Website, 2000-2005; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Wesker, Arnold, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Xerox, 1985-1990 (Box 10)
  - Zegers, Gerald, 2004 (Box 10)
  - Zesker, Murlyn, 1987 (Box 10)
- Media
  - Susan Nussbaum Scenes from Mishuganismo, shaktman_001; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - 1) Don't hang Up 2) We're Not Kidding, shaktman_002; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Ben Shaktman IMPACT Presentation Paris, Nov, 1999; shaktman_003; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - IMPACT Model Training Workshop, Jun, 2002; shaktman_004-shaktman_009; 6 VHSs (Box 12)
  - Nov 15 1999 tape 2, 15 Nov 1999; shaktman_010; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - System/390 Magazine, 1992; shaktman_011; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - AS/400 Report, Sep 1990; shaktman_012; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - AS/400 In an Open World, shaktman_013; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - AS/400 Advanced Series: That's The Beauty Of It, 3 May 1994; shaktman_014; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - AS/400 Extending Your Competitive Edge, shaktman_015; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Allied Welcome Home, 4 Oct 1991; shaktman_016; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - New York times Magazine Quality Gets Results (short version), 20 Feb 1991; shaktman_017; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Compilation Reel Part 2, 1 Oct 1991; shaktman_018; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Seminar For One #4, 19 Feb 1992; shaktman_019; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Attorneys & Macintosh: Partners For Success, 1992; shaktman_020; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Changing The Rules: The Jacksonville Story, shaktman_021; 1 VHS (Box 12)
  - Alice In Openland AS/400, 1992; shaktman_022; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - AZI 2004, shaktman_023; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - New Year Address 2006, Jan 2006; shaktman_024; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - AZI 2006, 1 Apr 2006; shaktman_025-shaktman_027; 3 DVDs (Box 12)
  - AZI 2007, 24 Mar 2007; shaktman_028-shaktman_030; 3 DVDs (Box 12)
  - AZI Diversity Video, 19 Mar 2007; shaktman_031; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Odysseus - Hero of Transformation, 2007; shaktman_032; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Analyst Conference, 13 Oct 1999; shaktman_033; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Emerging Technology Showcase, 8 Dec 2003; shaktman_034; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - CAD Camp 95, 1995; shaktman_035; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Virage Demo CD v.11, 2003; shaktman_036; 1 CD (Box 12)
  - Web Site Business Alignment: Attaining Measurable Value, 2004; shaktman_037; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Strap 2005, 6 Jan 2005; shaktman_038; 1 CD (Box 12)
  - Board Room 1201A, shaktman_039; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - IMPACT Executive Presentation Skills Workshop, Jun 2005; shaktman_040; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - GSM Session 10, shaktman_041; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - GSM Session 11, shaktman_042; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Delivering Project Excellence, 28 Jun 2005; shaktman_043; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Ben's Presentation, 28 Jun 2005; shaktman_044; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Ben Shaktman coaching an executive presentation, 1 Apr 2008; shaktman_045; 1 DVD (Box 12)
  - Photos and old website, 13 Feb 2008; shaktman_046; 1 CD (Box 12)
  - Alice in Openland Disk 1- Disk 4, shaktman_047-shaktman_050; 4 floppies (3-1/2 in.) (Box 12)
  - Present Yourself, shaktman_051; 1 floppy (3-1/2 in.) (Box 12)
  - IBM AS/400 Dick O'Dell Teleconference, 13 Dec 1996; shaktman_052; 1 floppy (3-1/2 in.) (Box 12)
  - Training Tape '94 Tape 1- Tape 4, 1994; shaktman_053-shaktman_056; 4 audio cassettes (Box 12)
  - S.A. Training Program Tape 1- Tape 9, 23 Feb 1994; shaktman_057-shaktman_065; 9 audio cassettes (Box 12)
  - Client Marketing Review Tape 10 - Tape 16, 28 Feb 1994; shaktman_066-shaktman_072; 7 audio cassettes (Box 12)
  - Sales Training Tape 1 - Tape 3, 3 Jun 1993; shaktman_073-shaktman_075; 3 audio cassettes (Box 12)
  - GIGA Facilitation, 17 Oct 2001; shaktman_076; 1 audio cassette (Box 12)
  - Effective Presentation Skills, shaktman_077; 1 floppy (3-1/2 in.) (Box 12)
  - Ben's Dynamics notes re: Credit Union/ Les Speech, 19 Aug 1988; shaktman_078; 1 audio cassette (Box 12)
  - Measures of Success in American Business today, 1988; shaktman_079; 1 audio cassette (Box 12)
  - Insead University Tape 1 - Tape 2, 1988; shaktman_080 - shaktman_081; 2 MiniDVs (Box 12)
  - Insead University Tape 1 - Tape 2, shaktman_080 - shaktman_081; 2 MiniDVs (Box 12)
  - GIGA interviews Tape 1 - Tape 2, 2002; shaktman_082 - shaktman_083; 2 MiniDVs (Box 12)
  - S.A. Productions Master Tape 1 - Tape 14, shaktman_084 - shaktman_097; 14 MiniDVs (Box 12)
- Memorabilia
  - Appointment calendars, 1987-2001 (Box 11)
  - Ben Shaktman diary "China Trip", 2000 (Box 10)
  - Phone logs, 1988-2005 (Box 11)
  - Photographs (Box 10)
- Publications
  - Brochure, 1987-2003 (Box 10)
  - "Don't Hang Up", 1992 (Box 10)
  - I.M.P.A.C.T. (Box 10)
  - "Managing Media Projects", 1986 (Box 10)
  - "Present Yourself!", 1984 (Box 10)
  - Presentation/Communication Skills Workshop material, 1994-2004 (Box 10)
  - "Writing Product (Technical) Brochures", 1991 (Box 10)